<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>GOOD.is</title>
    <description>Promote and empower what works.</description>
    <link>http://www.good.is/</link>
    <item>
      <title>
        <![CDATA[What Would You Share if You Found a Diary Tied to a Park Bench?]]>
      </title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>	<img alt="" id="asset_515602" src="http://pre.cloudfront.goodinc.com/posts/full_1389390612BDPHOTO1(1).jpg" /></p><p>	If you happened upon a diary tied to a bench with an invitation to write <em>anything</em> and the understanding that <em>anyone</em> can read your anonymous entry, what would you write?</p><p>	On a hot June day in Atlanta, GA, I decided to find out by tying four pink diaries to benches around the city and inviting my neighbors to write in them. Since that day, I have collected over 90 entries written on a wide range of subjects by people of all ages. I call the project <a href="http://www.benchdiary.com">Bench Diary</a>.</p><p>	When I was in high school, I found my fourth grade journal buried amongst other childhood memorabilia. The journal provided my friends and me with endless entertainment and sparked my fascination with diaries. I love the fearlessness and honesty that pours out of us when we write in diaries. I hope to inspire that fearlessness in people who write Bench Diary entries and in people who read those entries.</p><p>	Much to my delight, all four diaries I put out the first day contained wonderful entries. One person told a story of resorting to stripping for money, while a couple wrote an Exquisite Corpse-style poem about sitting in the park. I was totally hooked after that first day and wanted to learn much more about my neighbors.</p><p>	On Bench Diary days, I set out in the morning with several diaries, a ball of string, scissors, pens and my phone so I can share each diary&rsquo;s location on Instagram, Twitter and Facebook. Returning in the evening to retrieve each diary is a thrill, as I never know what to expect. The diary could be missing, or someone could be in the process of writing when I arrive. The diary could even be urinated on, as was the case with a diary I tied to a picnic table at a skate park. That certainly did not stop me from picking it up by a dry corner and tossing it in my trunk.</p><p>	The most common type of entry so far has been one sharing advice or wisdom.</p><p>	<img alt="" id="asset_515590" src="http://pre.cloudfront.goodinc.com/posts/full_1389390275BDPHOTO2(1).jpg" /><br />	&nbsp;</p><p>	People often write about the specific place or time.</p><p>	<img alt="" id="asset_515592" src="http://pre.cloudfront.goodinc.com/posts/full_1389390296BDPHOTO3.jpg" /></p><p>	Or they share a story.</p><p>	<img alt="" id="asset_515594" src="http://pre.cloudfront.goodinc.com/posts/full_1389390314BDPHOTO4(3).jpg" /><br />	&nbsp;</p><p>	Here is a story from the urine-soaked diary.</p><p>	<img alt="" id="asset_515596" src="http://pre.cloudfront.goodinc.com/posts/full_1389390404BDPHOTO5(2).jpg" /></p><p>	Though Bench Diary is anonymous, I do ask people to share their age. This entry was written by a 92-year-old.</p><p>	<img alt="" id="asset_515598" src="http://pre.cloudfront.goodinc.com/posts/full_1389390418BDPHOTO6(2).jpg" /><br />	&nbsp;</p><p>	Entries from children are my favorite entries to read.</p><p>	<img alt="" id="asset_515600" src="http://pre.cloudfront.goodinc.com/posts/full_1389390437BDPHOTO7(1).jpg" /></p><p>	I have been blown away by what my neighbors have chosen to share with complete strangers, and I cannot help but wonder what people in other cities and countries have to share. Eventually, I hope to establish a network of people all over the world who want to participate in the project by putting out Bench Diaries in their cities and submitting the entries they collect. We could build an amazing collection of entries spanning time, geography, culture and language.</p><p>	If you are interested in getting involved with the project by putting out Bench Diaries in your city, send me an email at <a href="mailto:benchdiary@gmail.com">benchdiary@gmail.com</a>. You can also get involved by following the project at benchdiary.com and on <a href="http://instagram.com/benchdiary">Instagram</a> and <a href="http://twitter.com/benchdiary">Twitter</a>&nbsp;by following @benchdiary and by liking Bench Diary on <a href="http://facebook.com/benchdiary">Facebook</a><strong>.</strong></p><p>	Check out my <a href="http://www.pechakucha.org/cities/atlanta/presentations/dear-bench-diary">PechaKucha presentation</a> on Bench Diary too.</p><p><em>We&#39;re growing the community of people sharing creative solutions for living well and doing good, and want you to be a part of it. If you have an insight, experience, idea, or project you want to share with the GOOD Community and need more space to tell your story than posting a link on <a href="http://good.is" target="_blank">good.is</a> allows, email us at <a href="mailto:community@goodinc.com" target="_blank">community@goodinc.com</a>.</em></em></p>]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 13:55:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.good.is/posts/what-would-you-share-if-you-found-a-diary-tied-to-a-park-bench</link>
      <guid>http://www.good.is/posts/what-would-you-share-if-you-found-a-diary-tied-to-a-park-bench</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>
        <![CDATA[RISE with One Billion Rising in DTLA - Call for flash mobbers & musicians!]]>
      </title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Join us on V-Day as we rise alongside our brothers and sisters across the globe to protest violence and injustice. Check for an event in your city, or start your own ! http://www.onebillionrising.org/

For Angelenos, the breakdown of our DTLA event:

12:30 pm: Flashmob at LA Live
12:35-12:40: Start walking from LA Live to City Hall
1:30: Mayor Garcetti to speak 
1:45: Lauren Turk performs "Grow"
2:00: Party, party, rise, rise to Break the Chain

I'm currently recruiting local musicians to share the stage with me as I perform Grow. If you would like to be a part of this day and movement, email me at laurenanatolia@gmail.com.

I'm looking for keys, drums, accordion, trumpet and bass !


**minor details are subject to change]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 13:06:19 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.good.is/posts/rise-with-one-billion-rising-in-dtla-call-for-flash-mobbers-musicians</link>
      <guid>http://www.good.is/posts/rise-with-one-billion-rising-in-dtla-call-for-flash-mobbers-musicians</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>
        <![CDATA[Innovation = Freeway Swings and Disco Ball Traffic Lights]]>
      </title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Have you ever looked at a street sign and thought, this could use a little humor? A little imagination? I love this series of sketches which dream up imaginative and fun ideas for cities. They come from Zisiadis' book "Urban Imagination." 

I'll take one rocking bench for my local bus stop, please! ]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2014 12:55:03 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.good.is/posts/innovation-freeway-swings-and-disco-ball-traffic-lights</link>
      <guid>http://www.good.is/posts/innovation-freeway-swings-and-disco-ball-traffic-lights</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>
        <![CDATA[Redesigning City Streets with a Mobile Phone]]>
      </title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>	<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/hazyuk/3318327851/"><img alt="" id="asset_515465" src="http://pre.cloudfront.goodinc.com/posts/full_1389234580_1cb8a4b907_b.jpg" /></a></p><p>		Have you ever asked yourself, &quot;What can I do today to make my city a better place to live?&quot;</p>	<p>		Up until a few years ago, it wouldn&#39;t have occurred to me to ask that question. My city was detached from the forces that managed it. I never had any expectation of influencing the place I called home. I went to work, exercised, paid my bills, hung out with my friends&mdash;and my city was simply the place where all those things occurred. It&#39;s not that I didn&#39;t have any ideas for improving the city; I just never thought about getting involved.&nbsp;</p>	<p>		When I attended SXSW Interactive in 2012, I heard two different women deliver speeches that changed how I thought about making change. One of those women was <a href="http://www.codeforamerica.org/author/jen/">Jennifer Pahlka</a>, the founder of Code for America. She got me thinking about the role of government and how open software could disrupt and improve the old ways of doing things. City services could become better and cheaper through open technology. Anthropologist <a href="http://www.ted.com/speakers/amber_case.html">Amber Case</a> informed all the conference attendees that we were technically cyborgs, being that we are attached to mobile devices that could allow us to become smarter and more efficient.</p>	<p>		I came back from the conference incredibly inspired by the possibilities of mobile devices enabling each of us to become a force of positive change in our cities. I thought to myself, many people don&#39;t have the time to sit in a city hall meeting to present their concerns and/or ideas to improve their city streets. A previous project with the Environmental Protection Agency of Victoria helped me realize that by connecting as many people as possible and providing the right open source tools, people can and will create positive change for themselves. I came up with an idea for a product so compelling I left my workplace in Melbourne and relocated to Austin, Texas, to begin work on my own startup.&nbsp;</p>	<p>		<a href="http://keytothestreet.com/">Key to the Street</a> is a cloud-based service that allows anyone with a mobile device to participate in the design of public spaces. The main focus is encouraging more people to walk&mdash;the cheapest and easiest way to improve one&#39;s wellbeing. I&#39;m starting with a focus on walking because most cities need to scale down to allow for this basic activity&mdash;to put the focus on health and sustainability. People are encouraged to use Key to the Street when they&#39;re physically standing at the exact location they hope to help improve. Everyone can share their ideas for better designs and learn from one another. Cities can become even better by enabling more people to participate in urban design.</p>	<p>		<a href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/jeslowry/key-to-the-street-the-future-of-urban-design"><img alt="" id="asset_515461" src="http://pre.cloudfront.goodinc.com/posts/full_1389233479ScreenShot2014-01-07at6.32.34PM.png" /></a></p>	<p>		The process begins with you standing in a street area you think needs improving and capturing a photo and the location info in the Key to the Streets app. You then have the option of either sketching and/or dragging/dropping elements on the photo to provide design ideas. There&#39;s also an option to send audio or a text message about your ideas.</p>	<p>		<a href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/jeslowry/key-to-the-street-the-future-of-urban-design"><img alt="" id="asset_515463" src="http://pre.cloudfront.goodinc.com/posts/full_1389233573ScreenShot2014-01-07at6.36.28PM.png" /></a></p>	<p>		Key to the Street then collects and analyzes this data for city planners to help them make well-informed decisions for redevelopment projects. Urban designers can use this data generated from local citizens to not only inspire design plans but also give proof to city government that there is a need for street redesign. As a result both citizens and designers accelerate the process of making their cities more walkable.&nbsp;</p><p>	<a href="http://keytothestreet.com/"><img alt="" id="asset_514636" src="http://pre.cloudfront.goodinc.com/posts/full_1386805837ScreenShot2013-12-11at3.34.40PM.png" /></a></p><p>		Please join my team by <a href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/jeslowry/key-to-the-street-the-future-of-urban-design">backing Key to the Street on Kickstarter</a>. The City of Austin is ready to use this tool in a pilot, but I can&#39;t deliver it until I&#39;m able to complete more of the development work. There is a plan for scaling the service quickly so that Key to the Street can be available in every city around the world and I&#39;ve already received interest in funding once the beta version is built.</p><p>		Anyone can use Key to the Street to create a project to improve any type of public space and invite others to collaborate on ideas. Whoever is interested in participating can use the design tool to sketch on top of a photo or image to submit different ideas.&nbsp;After the pilot is complete in Austin this spring, Key to the Street can be released globally and we&#39;ll all be able to use it anywhere in the world. Your support of <a href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/jeslowry/key-to-the-street-the-future-of-urban-design">Key to the Street on Kickstarter </a>today can help make your city a better place to live.</p><p>	<em>Images via (cc) Flickr user Alex Hayes and keytothestreet.com</em></p><p><em>This project is part of GOOD&#39;s series <a href="http://www.good.is/push-for-good">Push for Good</a>&mdash;our guide to crowdsourcing creative progress.</em></p><p><em>We&#39;re growing the community of people sharing creative solutions for living well and doing good, and want you to be a part of it. If you have an insight, experience, idea, or project you want to share with the GOOD Community and need more space to tell your story than posting a link on <a href="http://good.is" target="_blank">good.is</a> allows, email us at <a href="mailto:community@goodinc.com" target="_blank">community@goodinc.com</a>.</em></em></p>]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2014 10:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.good.is/posts/redesigning-city-streets-with-a-mobile-phone</link>
      <guid>http://www.good.is/posts/redesigning-city-streets-with-a-mobile-phone</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>
        <![CDATA[How to Build Sharing Cities]]>
      </title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[My latest post on how to build sharing cities -- and why Shareable's Sharing Cities Network is so important to make that happen.]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 06:36:26 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.good.is/posts/how-to-build-sharing-cities</link>
      <guid>http://www.good.is/posts/how-to-build-sharing-cities</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>
        <![CDATA[Are you inspired by the streets you tread each day?]]>
      </title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[What makes a street great? The bend of its curve? The local businesses? Street art? Green space?

There is no way any single designer, no matter how talented or skilled, could create these types of streets. They grow organically. Based on the needs of the people who are part of a particular culture. It's necessary to have a certain amount of chaos to make these streets work. But they also need to be nurtured in the right way because streets can die or become commodified and trapped in a false]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 17:54:20 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.good.is/posts/are-you-inspired-by-the-streets-you-tread-each-day</link>
      <guid>http://www.good.is/posts/are-you-inspired-by-the-streets-you-tread-each-day</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>
        <![CDATA[When Tech Culture And Urbanism Collide]]>
      </title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The city is the most complex machine ever invented. Running optimally, the city generates opportunity and provides a platform for interaction, ideas, and improvement. As a concept, the city has been iterated-upon, smashed and burnt to the ground, rebuilt, deliberately-designed, haphazardly-organized, and generally resilient for many millennia. But the city is still a human invention and every single one is flawed, many horribly so.]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 14:24:50 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.good.is/posts/when-tech-culture-and-urbanism-collide</link>
      <guid>http://www.good.is/posts/when-tech-culture-and-urbanism-collide</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>
        <![CDATA[Incorporate Charity Into our Daily Routine]]>
      </title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[I was inspired by this post from Mashable, that shows 6 mobile apps that help incorporate giving to charities into our daily lives.
]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 08:10:12 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.good.is/posts/incorporate-charity-into-our-daily-routine</link>
      <guid>http://www.good.is/posts/incorporate-charity-into-our-daily-routine</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>
        <![CDATA[Social Change via the Living Room]]>
      </title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Mike de la Rocha, founder of The Living Rooms Across America Tour, talks about the art of cross-sector convening and storytelling to tackle gun violence in the United States.]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 07:08:46 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.good.is/posts/social-change-via-the-living-room</link>
      <guid>http://www.good.is/posts/social-change-via-the-living-room</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>
        <![CDATA[Community & Collaborative Design]]>
      </title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Majora Carter, urban revitalization strategist, believes that "no community just becomes something, communities are made. You can design a community in many different ways but what is important is for people to become empowered and actually participate."   

In October 2013, the GOOD Austin chapter exercised this notion of participatory design by collaborating with SXSW Eco to curate a furniture building workshop, where all end products had a specific purpose and place in the Austin community.]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 11:15:13 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.good.is/posts/community-design</link>
      <guid>http://www.good.is/posts/community-design</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>
        <![CDATA[Street View For Bikes]]>
      </title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[As Cyclodeo founder Samir Bendida told Fast.Co Exist, Cyclodeo will probably be most useful for new riders, tourists, and people who'd want to explore a new city through a virtual bike. It could also help urban planners and bike advocates compare bike infrastructure across different cities. Many of the videos so far have been captured by Bendida himself. But now the company is inviting cyclists to “unlock their own cities," either by requesting Cyclodeo coverage there or contributing yourself.]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2013 14:45:53 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.good.is/posts/street-view-for-bikes</link>
      <guid>http://www.good.is/posts/street-view-for-bikes</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>
        <![CDATA[Five Solutions for Changing the Health of Our Communities]]>
      </title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The Institute of Medicine reaffirms that when it comes to our obesity problem we are quick to blame ourselves and other individuals in eating too much and exercising too little but there's more to that than just our behavior and decision making. 

Take a look at the IOM's infographic to understand that factors and causes of our nation's obesity trend along with the proposed solutions. The IOM says "anyone and everyone can be a leader and play a part in implementing these five solutions."]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2013 17:44:14 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.good.is/posts/five-solutions-for-changing-the-health-of-our-communities</link>
      <guid>http://www.good.is/posts/five-solutions-for-changing-the-health-of-our-communities</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>